Register of the Samuel Tankersley Williams papers, 1917-1980
Hoover Institution Archives
Samuel Tankersley Williams papers
1917-1980
81032
Hoover Institution Archives
24 manuscript boxes, 9 envelopes, 9 sound tape reels (10.7 linear feet)
Correspondence, speeches, orders, memoranda, reports, interview transcripts, conference notes, photographs, and sound recordings relating to American military activities in the European Theater during World War II, Amerian military operations in the Korean War, and American military assistance to South Vietnam.
Williams, S. T. (Samuel Tankersley), 1897-
Access
Collection is open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 1981.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the online catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Biographical Note
1897 August 25 Born, Denton, Texas
1916-1917 Private in the Texas Militia
1917 Attended Officers Training Camp, Leon Springs, Texas Commissioned Second Lieutenant, Officers Reserve Corps
1917-1919 359th Infantry Regiment, France; fought in battles of St. Michel, Meuse-Argonne, and Toul Sector
1920 Commissioned First Lieutenant in regular United States Army
1925-1926 Attended Company Officers Course, Fort Benning, Georgia
1926-1930 Captain, 21st Infantry Regiment, Hawaii
1930-1931 Attended United States Army Infantry Officers Advance Course
1933-1935 Attended United States Army Command and General Staff School
1935-1937 Company commander, 29th Infantry Regiment, Fort Benning, Georgia
1937-1938 Attended Army War College
1943-1944 Brigadier General, commander of the 378th Infantry Regiment and assistant division commander of the 90th Infantry Division, France; landed on Utah Beach
1944 Demoted from Brigadier General to Colonel
1944-1945 G-3 of the XXII Corps, European Theater of Operations
1946-1950 Commander of the 26th Infantry Regiment and acting commanding general of the 1st Infantry Division, Nuremberg
1950-1952 Served in Operations and Training Office of the Army Field Forces, Fort Monroe, Virginia
1951 Promoted to Brigadier General
1952-1953 Commander of the 25th Infantry Division, Korea
1953 Promoted to Major General
1953-1954 Commander of the XVI Corps, Japan
1954 Commander of the IX Corps and deputy commander of the Eighth Army, Korea
1955 Deputy commander of the Fourth Army, Fort Sam Houston, Texas
1955 Promoted to Lieutenant General
1955-1960 Chief of the Military Assistance and Advisory Group (MAAG), Vietnam
1984 April 26 Died, San Antonio, Texas
Scope and Content of Collection
Correspondence, speeches, orders, memoranda, reports, interview transcripts, conference notes, photographs, and sound recordings relating to American military activities in the European Theater during World War II, Amerian military operations in the Korean War, and American military assistance to South Vietnam.
United States. Army--Officers.; United States. Military Assistance Advisory Group, Vietnam.; Korean War, 1950-1953.; Military assistance, American--Vietnam.; Phonotapes.; United States--Armed Forces.; Vietnam.; World War, 1939-1945--Campaigns--Western.; World War, 1939-1945.
- EARLY MILITARY CAREER FILE, 1917-1947 (Box 1)
  Scope and Contents note
  Clippings, reports, and fliers, arranged alphabetically by subject.
  - Command and General Staff School, 1921 (Box-folder 1: 1)
  - Efficiency reports, 1929-1947 (Box-folder 1: 2)
  - First Officer Training Camp, Leon Springs, Texas, 1917 (Box-folder 1: 3)
  - 378th Infantry Regiment, 1942 (Box-folder 1: 4)
- 90TH INFANTRY DIVISION, FRANCE FILE, 1943-1944 (Box 1)
  Correspondence, notes, memoranda, and maps, arranged by subject.
  - Demotion in rank from Brigadier General to Colonel (Box-folder 1: 5)
  - Operation Overlord
    - Battle plans and maps (Box-folder 1: 6-9)
    - Memoranda (Box-folder 1: 10)
    - Notes (Box-folder 1: 11)
      Describes daily troop activities from 3 June to 14 August 1944.
- XXII CORPS, EUROPEAN THEATER OF OPERATIONS FILE, 1944-1945 (Box 2)
  Clippings, correspondence, memoranda, and reports, arranged by physical format.
  - Clippings (Box-folder 2: 1)
  - Correspondence
    - General (Box-folder 2: 2)
    - Yates, Eames L., 1944 (Box-folder 2: 3)
  - Memoranda (Box-folder 2: 4)
  - Miscellaneous (Box-folder 2: 5)
  - Reports
    - "History of the XXII Corps in the Rhineland, 1945 March 20-June 16," typescript, circa 1945 (Box-folder 2: 6)
    - "Report of Operations for Period 8 May 1945 to 30 September 1945," typescript, circa 1945 (Box-folder 2: 7)
- 26TH INFANTRY REGIMENT, NUREMBERG FILE, 1945-1950 (Boxes 2-4)
  Correspondence, clippings, maps, memoranda, ordinances, and reports, arranged by physical format or subject. Includes material on the International Military Tribunal.
  - Correspondence, 1945-1950
    - Official (Box-folder 2: 8)
    - Personal
      - General (Box-folder 2: 9)
      - Abrams, Lt. Col. Creighton, 1950 (Box-folder 2: 10)
      - Clayton, Maj. George, 1950 (Box-folder 2: 11)
      - Everett, Carl, 1950 (Box-folder 2: 12)
      - Harman, Ernest, 1947 (Box-folder 2: 13)
      - Harmony, Col. Jack, 1949 (Box-folder 2: 14)
      - Harris, Ida Ann, 1950 (Box-folder 2: 15)
      - Milburn, Gen. F.W., 1947-1950 (Box-folder 2: 16)
      - Rogers, Maj. Gen. Pleas B., 1949 (Box-folder 2: 17)
      - Seitz, Mr. and Mrs. Jeff, 1950 (Box-folder 2: 18)
      - Steinhardt, Laurence, 1945-1946 (Box-folder 2: 19)
      - Stilwell, Lt. Col. Richard, 1949 (Box-folder 2: 20)
      - Williams, Ed P. (Samuel Williams' brother), 1950 (Box-folder 2: 21)
  - Clippings (Box-folder 2: 22)
  - International Military Tribunal, Nuremberg
    - General (Box-folder 2: 23)
    - Memoranda (Box-folder 2: 24)
    - Ordinances
      - General (Box-folder 2: 25)
      - Security detachment (Box-folder 2: 26)
    - Reports
      - Interrogation of Admiral Karl Doenitz (Box-folder 3: 1)
      - Mistreatment of German prisoners of war (Box-folder 3: 2)
        Relates to the case of Udo v. Woyrsch, former SS officer.
      - Transcripts of court proceedings (Box-folder 3: 3-7)
  - Maps (Box-folder 3: 8)
  - Memoranda (Box-folder 4: 1)
  - Miscellaneous (Box-folder 4: 2)
  - Reports (Box-folder 4: 3)
- 25TH INFANTRY DIVISION, KOREA FILE, 1952-1953 (Boxes 4-5)
  Correspondence, memoranda, notes, reports, and speeches, arranged by physical format.
  - Correspondence, 1952-1953
    - Commendations (Box-folder 4: 4)
      Includes Lt. Gen. Williams' Distinguished Service Cross, Silver Star, and Gold Star Ulchi Medal.
    - Congratulatory letters
      - A-M (Box-folder 4: 5)
      - N-Z (Box-folder 4: 6)
    - Official
      - General (Box-folder 4: 7)
      - Adams, Maj. Gen. Paul D., 1952-1953 (Box-folder 4: 8)
      - Bendetsen, Karl, 1952 (Box-folder 4: 9)
      - Chung, Gen. Il Kwon, 1953 (Box-folder 4: 10)
      - Clarke, Maj. Gen. Bruce, 1953 (Box-folder 4: 11)
      - Crawford, Col. Joseph, 1953 (Box-folder 4: 12)
      - Eschenberg, Col. Emil P., 1953 (Box-folder 4: 13)
      - Finn, Col. Russ, 1952 (Box-folder 4: 14)
      - Lindeman, Col. Philip F., 1953 (Box-folder 4: 15)
      - Paik, Gen. Sun Yup, 1953 (Box-folder 4: 16)
      - Taylor, Col. B. Frank, 1953 (Box-folder 4: 17)
      - Taylor, Lt. Gen. Maxwell, 1953 (Box-folder 4: 18)
      - Van Fleet, Gen. James A., 1953 (Box-folder 4: 19)
      - White, Lt. Gen. I. D., 1953 (Box-folder 4: 20)
    - Personal
      - General (Box-folder 4: 21)
      - Acar, Brig. Gen. Sirri, 1952 (Box-folder 4: 22)
      - Blazey, Mrs. Frank, 1952 (Box-folder 4: 23)
      - Browne, Homer, 1952 (Box-folder 4: 24)
      - Bykerk, Lt. Col. Norman H., 1952 (Box-folder 4: 25)
      - Cagwin, Lt. Col. Leland G., 1952 (Box-folder 4: 26)
      - Case, Lt. Col. Charlie, 1953 (Box-folder 4: 27)
      - Chung, Lt. Gen. Il Kwon, 1953 (Box-folder 4: 28)
      - Clayton, Lt. Col. George, 1952-1953 (Box-folder 4: 29)
      - Coates, Harry, 1952 (Box-folder 4: 30)
      - Corley, Col. John, 1953 (Box-folder 4: 31)
      - Dobol, M/Sgt. Theodore, 1952-1953 (Box-folder 5: 1)
      - Donnelly, Maj. Ross, 1953 (Box-folder 5: 2)
      - Egbert, C. A., 1952-1953 (Box-folder 5: 3)
      - Finn, Col. Russ, 1952 (Box-folder 5: 4)
      - Fritzsche, Brig. Gen. Carl, 1953 (Box-folder 5: 5)
      - Harkins, Maj. Gen. Paul, 1953 (Box-folder 5: 6)
      - Harris, Herbert, 1953 (Box-folder 5: 7)
      - Hilburn, Herbert, 1953 (Box-folder 5: 8)
      - Huebner, Lt. Gen. Clarence R., 1952 (Box-folder 5: 9)
      - Lemberes, Capt. Albert, 1953 (Box-folder 5: 10)
      - Ordoyne, Capt. Lucien, 1953 (Box-folder 5: 11)
      - Paik, Brig. Gen. In Yup, 1952 (Box-folder 5: 12)
      - Paik, Lt. Gen. Sun Yup, 1952 (Box-folder 5: 13)
      - Phinney, Maj. Gen. Carl, 1952-1953 (Box-folder 5: 14)
      - Ridgway, Gen. M. B., 1952 (Box-folder 5: 15)
      - Taylor, Col. B. Frank, 1953 (Box-folder 5: 16)
      - Trudeau, Maj. Gen. Arthur G., 1953 (Box-folder 5: 17)
      - White, Maj. Gen. I. D., 1952 (Box-folder 5: 18)
  - Memoranda (Box-folder 5: 19-20)
  - Notes (Assistant Division Commander's staff)
    - Crawford, Col. Joseph (Box-folder 5: 21)
    - Fritzsche, Maj. Gen. Carl (Box-folder 5: 22-23)
  - Reports
    - "History, Concepts, Effects of Moslem Religion in Turkey," typescript (Box-folder 5: 24)
    - Patrol study (Box-folder 5: 25)
    - Standing Operating Procedures (SOP) (Box-folder 5: 26)
  - Speeches by Gen. Mark W. Clark (Box-folder 5: 27)
- XVI CORPS, JAPAN FILE, 1953-1954 (Boxes 6-7)
  Correspondence, memoranda, and reports, arranged by physical format.
  - Correspondence, 1953-1954
    - Commendations (Box-folder 6: 1)
    - Congratulatory letters (Box-folder 6: 2)
    - Official
      - General (Box-folder 6: 3)
      - Dul, Maj. Peter, 1953 (Box-folder 6: 4)
      - Japanese officials, 1953-1954 (Box-folder 6: 5)
      - Taylor, Gen. Maxwell, 1954 (Box-folder 6: 6)
    - Personal
      - General (Box-folder 6: 7)
      - Acar, Brig. Gen. Sirri, 1953-1954 (Box-folder 6: 8)
      - Aloe, Col. Robert C., 1953-1954 (Box-folder 6: 9)
      - Brown, Homer, 1954 (Box-folder 6: 10)
      - Cagwin, Col. L. G., 1953-1954 (Box-folder 6: 11)
      - Carter, Maj. Gen. Leslie D., 1953-1954 (Box-folder 6: 12)
      - Chung, Lt. Gen. Il Kwon, 1953-1954 (Box-folder 6: 13)
      - Clarke, Lt. Gen. Bruce C., 1953-1954 (Box-folder 6: 14)
      - Crawford, Brig. Gen. Joseph, 1953 (Box-folder 6: 15)
      - Dasher, Maj. Gen. Charles L., 1953 (Box-folder 6: 16)
      - Egbert, C. A., 1953-1954 (Box-folder 6: 17)
      - Finn, Col. Russ T., 1953 (Box-folder 6: 18)
      - Fritzsche, Brig. Gen. Carl F., 1953 (Box-folder 6: 19)
      - Gray, Col. David W., 1953-1954 (Box-folder 6: 20)
      - Huebner, Lt. Gen. C. Ralph, 1953 (Box-folder 6: 21)
      - Kendall, Lt. Gen. Paul W., 1953 (Box-folder 6: 22)
      - Lindeman, Col. Philip F., 1953 (Box-folder 6: 23)
      - Magruder, Maj. Gen. Carter B., 1954 (Box-folder 6: 24)
      - Maroun, Col. Autrey J., 1954 (Box-folder 6: 25)
      - Mead, Maj. Gen. A. D., 1953-1954 (Box-folder 6: 26)
      - Ordoyne, Capt. Lucien, 1953 (Box-folder 6: 27)
      - Paik, Gen. Sun Yup, 1954 (Box-folder 6: 28)
      - Phinney, Maj. Gen. Carl L., 1953-1954 (Box-folder 6: 29)
      - Taylor, Col. B. Frank, 1954 (Box-folder 6: 30)
      - Trudeau, Maj. Gen. Arthur T., 1953 (Box-folder 6: 31)
      - White, Lt. Gen. I. D., 1953 (Box-folder 6: 32)
  - Memoranda (Box-folder 7: 1-3)
  - Report, Standing Operating Procedures (SOP) (Box-folder 7: 4)
- IX CORPS, KOREA FILE, 1954 (Boxes 7-8)
  Biographical material, correspondence, memoranda, and reports, arranged by physical format.
  - Biographical file (Box-folder 7: 5)
  - Correspondence, 1954
    - Congratulatory letters (Box-folder 7: 6)
    - Official
      - General (Box-folder 7: 7)
      - Canham, Maj. Gen. Charles D., 1954 (Box-folder 7: 8)
      - Chung, Brig. Gen. Il Kwon, 1954 (Box-folder 7: 9)
      - Clarke, Lt. Gen. Bruce C., 1954 (Box-folder 7: 10)
      - Seitz, Brig. Gen. John F. R., 1954 (Box-folder 7: 11)
      - Taylor, Gen. Maxwell, 1954 (Box-folder 7: 12)
    - Personal
      - General (Box-folder 7: 13)
      - Acar, Gen. Sirri, 1954 (Box-folder 7: 14)
      - Adams, Maj. Gen. Paul D., 1954 (Box-folder 7: 15)
      - Cagwin, Col. Lee, 1954 (Box-folder 7: 16)
      - Carter, Maj. Gen. Leslie D., 1954 (Box-folder 7: 17)
      - Chase, Col. Charles H., 1954 (Box-folder 7: 18)
      - Chung, Gen. Il Kwon, 1954 (Box-folder 7: 19)
      - Clarke, Lt. Gen. Bruce C., 1954 (Box-folder 7: 20)
      - Dobol, M/Sgt. Theodore, 1954 (Box-folder 7: 21)
      - Donnelly, Mrs. Ross, 1954 (Box-folder 7: 22)
      - Egbert, C. A., 1954 (Box-folder 7: 23)
      - Finn, Col. Russ T., 1954 (Box-folder 7: 24)
      - Fritzsche, Brig. Gen. Carl F., 1954 (Box-folder 7: 25)
      - Gray, Col. David W., 1954 (Box-folder 7: 26)
      - Hilburn, Herbert, 1954 (Box-folder 7: 27)
      - Kendall, Lt. Gen. Paul W., 1954 (Box-folder 7: 28)
      - Magruder, Lt. Gen. Carter B., 1954 (Box-folder 7: 29)
      - Maroun, Col. Autrey J., 1954 (Box-folder 7: 30)
      - Moses, Col. Lloyd R., 1954 (Box-folder 7: 31)
      - Phinney, Maj. Gen. Carl L., 1954 (Box-folder 7: 32)
      - Seitz, Brig. Gen. John F. R., 1954 (Box-folder 7: 33)
    - Thank you letters (Box-folder 7: 34)
  - Memoranda
    - General (Box-folder 8: 1-2)
    - Disciplinary action (Box-folder 8: 3)
    - Policies of the Corps Commander (Box-folder 8: 4)
  - Report, "Inspection Check List," typescript (Box-folder 8: 5)
  - Writings, "The Corps in Korea: A Brief Informal History of IX Corps (Group) in Korea from 23 September 1950 to 1 September 1954," co-author with Maj. Gen. Charles D.W. Canham, printed copy, undated (Box-folder 8: 6)
- EIGHTH ARMY, KOREA FILE, 1954 (Boxes 8-9)
  Biographical material, correspondence, and memoranda, arranged by physical format.
  - Biographical file
    - Korean military officers (Box-folder 8: 7)
    - Williams, Lt. Gen. Samuel T. (Box-folder 8: 8)
  - Correspondence, 1954
    - Congratulatory letters (Box-folder 8: 9)
    - Commendations (Box-folder 8: 10)
    - Official (Box-folder 8: 11)
    - Personal
      - General (Box-folder 8: 12)
      - Adams, Maj. Gen. Paul D., 1954 (Box-folder 8: 13)
      - Choi, Lt. Gen. Yong Hi, 1954 (Box-folder 8: 14)
      - Chung, Gen. Il Kwon, 1954 (Box-folder 8: 15)
      - Coates, Mrs. Harry, 1954 (Box-folder 8: 16)
      - Crawford, Brig. Gen. Joseph, 1954 (Box-folder 8: 17)
      - Dobol, M/Sgt. Theodore, 1954 (Box-folder 8: 18)
      - Donnelly, Mrs. Ross, 1954 (Box-folder 8: 19)
      - Egbert, C. A., 1954 (Box-folder 8: 20)
      - Eschenberg, Col. Emil, 1954 (Box-folder 8: 21)
      - Harris, Herbert, 1954 (Box-folder 8: 22)
      - Harris, Ida Ann (Samuel Williams' niece), 1954 (Box-folder 8: 23)
      - Huebner, Lt. Gen. C.R., 1954 (Box-folder 8: 24)
      - Lindeman, Brig. Gen. Philip F., 1954 (Box-folder 8: 25)
      - MacBride, 1st Lt. George, 1954 (Box-folder 9: 1)
      - Magruder, Lt. Gen. Carter, 1954 (Box-folder 9: 2)
      - Mead, Maj. Gen. A. D., 1954 (Box-folder 9: 3)
      - Moses, Col. Lloyd R., 1954 (Box-folder 9: 4)
      - Paik, Maj. Gen. In Yup, 1954 (Box-folder 9: 5)
      - Paik, Gen. Sun Yup, 1954 (Box-folder 9: 6)
      - Phinney, Maj. Gen. Carl, 1954 (Box-folder 9: 7)
      - Ridgway, Gen. M. B., 1954 (Box-folder 9: 8)
      - Sohn, Col. Hi Sun, 1954 (Box-folder 9: 9)
      - Song, Brig. Gen. Suk Ha, 1954 (Box-folder 9: 10)
      - White, Brig. Gen. I. D., 1954 (Box-folder 9: 11)
      - Williams, Charles (Samuel Williams' brother), 1954 (Box-folder 9: 12)
  - Memoranda (Box-folder 9: 13)
  - Writings, "Military Handbook," typescript, undated (Box-folder 9: 14)
    Describes the history and insignia and lists the commanding officers of United States and Korean corps and divisions.
- FOURTH ARMY, FORT SAM HOUSTON, TEXAS FILE, 1955 (Boxes 9-11)
  Biographical material, correspondence, and speeches, arranged by physical format.
  - Biographical file (Box-folder 9: 15)
    Contains Williams' military personnel file.
  - Correspondence, 1955
    - Congratulatory letters (Box-folder 9: 16)
    - Personal
      - General
        - A-G (Box-folder 9: 17)
        - H-L (Box-folder 9: 18)
        - M-P (Box-folder 10: 1)
        - R-Z (Box-folder 10: 2)
      - Acar, Maj. Gen. Sirri (Box-folder 10: 3)
      - Barnes, Brig. Gen. Wallace H. (Box-folder 10: 4)
      - Beach, Brig. Gen. D. E. (Box-folder 10: 5)
      - Berry, Maj. Gen. K. L. (Box-folder 10: 6)
      - Bielss, Maj. August C. (Box-folder 10: 7)
      - Booth, Maj. Gen. Donald P. (Box-folder 10: 8)
      - Brucker, Wilbur M. (Box-folder 10: 9)
      - Cagwin, Col. Lee G. (Box-folder 10: 10)
      - Canham, Maj. Gen. Charles D. (Box-folder 10: 11)
      - Chung, Gen. Il Kwon (Box-folder 10: 12)
      - Clarke, Lt. Gen. Bruce C. (Box-folder 10: 13)
      - Clayton, Col. George A. (Box-folder 10: 14)
      - Clinger, Maj. Gen. Sherman T. (Box-folder 10: 15)
      - Coates, Mr. and Mrs. Harry (Box-folder 10: 16)
      - Crawford, Brig. Gen. Joseph B. (Box-folder 10: 17)
      - Dahlquist, Gen. John E. (Box-folder 10: 18)
      - Day, Maj. Gen. Francis M. (Box-folder 10: 19)
      - Dobol, M/Sgt. Theodore (Box-folder 10: 20)
      - Donnelly, Maj. Ross (Box-folder 10: 21)
      - Eschenberg, Col. Emil E. (Box-folder 10: 22)
      - Everett, Carl (Box-folder 10: 23)
      - Fleming, Maj. Gen. Raymond H. (Box-folder 10: 24)
      - Fritzsche, Brig. Gen. Carl F. (Box-folder 10: 25)
      - Fry, Maj. Gen. J. C. (Box-folder 10: 26)
      - Fulbright, J. William (Box-folder 10: 27)
      - Gallagher, Maj. Gen. Phil E. (Box-folder 10: 28)
      - Harkins, Maj. Gen. Paul D. (Box-folder 10: 29)
      - Harris, Ed (Box-folder 10: 30)
      - Harris, Mr. and Mrs. Woodson (Samuel Williams' sister, Mary) (Box-folder 10: 31)
      - Harrold, Maj. Gen. Thomas L. (Box-folder 10: 32)
      - Hilburn, Herbert S. (Box-folder 10: 33)
      - Howze, Maj. Gen. R. L. (Box-folder 10: 34)
      - Johnson, Maj. Gen. Albert S. (Box-folder 10: 35)
      - Johnson, Brig. Gen. Edwin L. (Box-folder 10: 36)
      - Johnson, Lyndon B. (Box-folder 10: 37)
      - Johnston, Col. Robert O. (Box-folder 10: 38)
      - Kilday, Paul J. (Box-folder 10: 39)
      - Kenny, Maj. Gen. Roy W. (Box-folder 10: 40)
      - Klein, Maj. Gen. John A. (Box-folder 10: 41)
      - Korthy, Fred (Box-folder 10: 42)
      - Krueger, Gen. Walter (Box-folder 10: 43)
      - Lambert, Capt. Jack E. (Box-folder 10: 44)
      - Lindeman, Brig. Gen. Philip E. (Box-folder 10: 45)
      - McBride, 1st Lt. George (Box-folder 10: 46)
      - Magruder, Carter B. (Box-folder 11: 1)
      - Maroun, Autrey (Box-folder 11: 2)
      - Mead, Maj. Gen. A. D. (Box-folder 11: 3)
      - Moses, Col. Lloyd R. (Box-folder 11: 4)
      - O'Daniel, Lt. Gen. John W. (Box-folder 11: 5)
      - Ordoyne, Capt. Lucien (Box-folder 11: 6)
      - Paik, Gen. Sun Yup (Box-folder 11: 7)
      - Phinney, Maj. Gen. Carl L. (Box-folder 11: 8)
      - Randolph, A. Kennedy (Box-folder 11: 9)
      - Rhee, Syngman (Box-folder 11: 10)
      - Ruggles, William B. (Box-folder 11: 11)
      - Rutledge, Maj. Gen. Paul W. (Box-folder 11: 12)
      - Sage, Maj. Gen. Charles G. (Box-folder 11: 13)
      - Song, Lt. Gen. Yo Chen (Box-folder 11: 14)
      - Spear, Charles (Box-folder 11: 15)
      - Stilwell, Col. Richard (Box-folder 11: 16)
      - Taylor, Col. Henry F. (Box-folder 11: 17)
      - Taylor, Gen. Maxwell D. (Box-folder 11: 18)
      - Trudeau, Maj. Gen. Arthur G. (Box-folder 11: 19)
      - Weible, Lt. Gen. Walter L. (Box-folder 11: 20)
      - Weyland, Gen. O. P. (Box-folder 11: 21)
      - White, Lt. Gen. I. D. (Box-folder 11: 22)
      - Williams, Ed P. (Samuel Williams' brother) (Box-folder 11: 23)
      - Williams, Ed Paxton, Jr. (Samuel Williams' nephew) (Box-folder 11: 24)
      - Williams, Maj. Gen. Edward T. (Box-folder 11: 25)
      - Williams, Pauline (Box-folder 11: 26)
      - Woolfey, Brig. Gen. Francis (Box-folder 11: 27)
      - Yates, Maj. James, Jr. (Box-folder 11: 28)
    - Telephone conversations, transcripts (Box-folder 11: 29)
  - Office file, military districts
    - Arkansas (Box-folder 11: 30)
    - Louisiana (Box-folder 11: 31)
    - New Mexico (Box-folder 11: 32)
    - Oklahoma (Box-folder 11: 33)
  - Speeches
    - By others, typescript (Box-folder 11: 34)
    - By Samuel Williams
      - Unidentified, typescript, undated (Box-folder 11: 35)
      - Shreveport Chamber of Commerce, Shreveport, Louisiana, typescript, circa 1955 (Box-folder 11: 36)
      - Military intelligence reservists, typescript, circa 1955 (Box-folder 11: 37)
      - 22nd anniversary of Fourth Army, typescript, circa 1955 (Box-folder 11: 38)
      - Annual meeting of Chamber of Commerce, Snyder, Texas, typescript, 1955 January 22 (Box-folder 11: 39)
      - Louisiana National Guard Association Annual Meeting, Layfayette, Louisiana, typescript, 1955 February 4 (Box-folder 11: 40)
      - Military Personnel Procurement Conference, San Antonio, Texas, typescript, 1955 February 14 (Box-folder 11: 41)
      - Flag Day, Shreveport, Louisiana, typescript, 1955 June 14 (Box-folder 11: 42)
      - Sports banquet, Fort Sam Houston, Texas, typescript, 1955 July 28 (Box-folder 11: 43)
- MILITARY ASSISTANCE ADVISORY GROUP (MAAG), VIETNAM FILE, 1955-1960 (Boxes 12-16)
  - Biographical file (Box-folder 12: 1)
    Includes retirement, 31 August 1960.
  - Correspondence, 1955-1960
    - Correspondence lists (Box-folder 12: 2)
    - General
      - Unidentified (Box-folder 12: 3)
      - A-J (Box-folder 12: 4)
      - K-Y (Box-folder 12: 5)
    - Adams, Lt. Gen. Paul D., 1959 (Box-folder 12: 6)
    - Aloe, Brig. Gen. Robert C., 1958 (Box-folder 12: 7)
    - Bergquist, Gen. Earl C., 1956 (Box-folder 12: 8)
    - Browne, Homer, 1956-1958 (Box-folder 12: 9)
    - Brucker, Wilbur M., 1956-1959 (Box-folder 12: 10)
    - Bykerk, Col. Norman, 1956-1959 (Box-folder 12: 11)
    - Cagwin, Col. Leland G., 1956-1958 (Box-folder 12: 12)
    - Chase, Brig. Gen. Charles H., 1956 (Box-folder 12: 13)
    - Chieu-Thanh, Emperor of Annam, 1960 (Box-folder 12: 14)
    - Choi, Lt. Gen. Young Hi, 1960 (Box-folder 12: 15)
    - Chung, Gen. Il Kwon, 1956 (Box-folder 12: 16)
    - Clarke, Gen. Bruce C., 1956-1958 (Box-folder 12: 17)
    - Coates, Harry, 1958 (Box-folder 12: 18)
    - Crawford, Brig. Gen. Joseph B., 1956-1958 (Box-folder 12: 19)
    - Dittmar, Gus C., 1959 (Box-folder 12: 20)
    - Dobol, M/Sgt. Theodore, 1956-1959 (Box-folder 12: 21)
    - Dolph, Brig. Gen. Cyrus A., III, 1958-1959 (Box-folder 12: 22)
    - Donnelly, Maj. Ross, 1958 (Box-folder 12: 23)
    - Dul, Maj. Peter, 1956 (Box-folder 12: 24)
    - Duong-Van-Minh, Gen. (Big Minh), 1956 (Box-folder 12: 25)
    - Eddleman, Lt. Gen. Clyde D., 1956 (Box-folder 12: 26)
    - Edwards, M/Sgt. and Mrs. William, 1956-1958 (Box-folder 12: 27)
    - Everett, Carl, 1956 (Box-folder 12: 28)
    - Finn, Col. John M., 1956 (Box-folder 12: 29)
    - Fritzsche, Maj. Gen. Carl F., 1956-1958 (Box-folder 12: 30)
    - Fry, Maj. Gen. James C., 1956 (Box-folder 12: 31)
    - Gallagher, Maj. Gen. Philip E., 1958 (Box-folder 12: 32)
    - Garrison, Col. Lloyd R., 1958-1959 (Box-folder 12: 33)
    - Gray, Brig. Gen. David W., 1956 (Box-folder 12: 34)
    - Harmony, Maj. Gen. John W., 1956-1958 (Box-folder 12: 35)